Tufts University Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staff UP094
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts University Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staff
1949 -- 1968
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Tufts University
UP094
0.25 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Custodial History
Found in basement of Ballou Hall on Tufts campus in Summer 2010.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains an incomplete collection of administrative and teaching staff directory information for Tufts University.
Biographical / Historical
Since 1955, Tufts University has continued to expand its horizons. In 1964, in one of Wessell's final acts as president, Tufts opened the Experimental College. The Ex-College, which allows students to take classes not normally found in the curriculum, has remained one of Tufts' most popular programs.
In 1977, Tufts established a five-year joint degree program with the New England Conservatory of Music. Soon after, in 1979, a similar program began with the School of the Museum of Fine Arts. Also in 1979, the Tufts Center for European Studies in Talloires, France, was established in an 11th Century priory. The Tufts European Center began operation soon after.
In late 1979, Tufts made another important addition. In October, the Tufts University School of Veterinary Medicine opened at its original Boston campus. In 1980, the Grafton campus, built on the site of a state mental hospital, officially opened its doors.
The last two major additions to Tufts University took place in 1980 and 1981. In 1980, the Sackler School of Graduate Biomedical Sciences, established with a large grant from the Sackler family, opened its doors on the Boston campus of the Tufts School of Medicine. In 1981, at the Medford Campus, Tufts celebrated the opening of the School of Nutrition Science and Policy. The school was the first of its kind in the nation.
Since Tufts College was officially established in 1852, it has continued to grow and expand in new directions. From its beginnings as a small liberal arts college through its expansion into a full-scale university, Tufts has maintained a strong academic tradition and a community feel.
- Tufts University Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staff, 1949 -- 1968; UP094.001; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains an incomplete collection of administrative and teaching staff directory information for Tufts University.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1949-06-01; UP094.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Copy in reading room.
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1950-05-01; UP094.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1951-06-01; UP094.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1952-06-01; UP094.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1953-10-01; UP094.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1954-09-01; UP094.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1955-09-01; UP094.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1956-09-01; UP094.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1957-09-01; UP094.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1958-09-01; UP094.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staffs, 1959-09-01; UP094.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staff, 1960-09-01; UP094.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staff, 1961-09-01; UP094.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Administrative and Teaching Staff, 1962-09-01; UP094.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Staff Directory, 1963-09-01; UP094.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Staff Directory, 1954-09-01; UP094.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Staff Directory, 1965-09-01; UP094.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Staff Directory, 1966-09-01; UP094.001.001.00018 (Box 1)
  - Staff Directory, 1967-09-01; UP094.001.001.00019 (Box 1)
  - Staff Directory, 1968-09-01; UP094.001.001.00020 (Box 1)